SYLENS: So … you're even more extraordinary than I thought.
ALOY: I never had a mother.
SYLENS: What are you talking about? You had two, a dead woman and a machine.
ALOY: I'm not a person, I'm an instrument, manufactured by a machine.
ALOY: Born in destruction and fire.
SYLENS: To quench the flames and heal the world.
SYLENS: How tragic to learn you're a person of towering importance.
SYLENS: It seems you have a destiny to fulfil.
SYLENS: So when you're done feeling sorry for yourself, go to the Bitter Climb.
SYLENS: I'll be waiting above in Gaia Prime's ruins.
ALOY: Gaia's sacrifice, it did this?
ALOY: Cracked the inside of the mountain like it was an egg?
SYLENS, THROUGH FOCUS: Yes, yes, quickly now.
SYLENS: I've prepared the way ahead for you.
ALOY: So you've been in here before?
SYLENS: To a point. You'll see.
ALOY: You made a climbing path for me,
but left an army of machines for me to deal with?
SYLENS: Since when were machines any obstacle for you?
SYLENS: If you could fly, I wouldn't have bothered with a climbing path either.
ALOY: Don't look down, don't look down.
ALOY: Ugh, dammit!
ALOY: This is exactly the kind of place I expected to find you in, Sylens.
SYLENS: Thank you.
SYLENS: It's one of many workshops I have constructed over the years.
For years I tried to get through this hatch.
I drilled, I burned, I blasted.
But we both know that you won't have any trouble getting through.
You make it sound like I should apologise.
Not at all.
It never occurred to me that the way through
would not be with force, but with a key.
A key in human form.
The failure of imagination was mine, not yours.
Looks like you've spent a lot of time here.
Nineteen years ago, a great explosion destroyed this mountain.
Gaia's death, your birth.
The echo could be heard as far as The Claim.
Ash darkened the skies.
How they fretted in Meridian as they tried to read this omen.
The crater burned for weeks, but when it cooled
I was the first to behold what lay within.
Over time the machines closed ranks to protect it. Useful.
Soon no-one dared to come here, except me.
In her message Gaia said we could restore her,
but after seeing the damage, how could that be?
She said any effort to repair her must come after Hades is destroyed.
I concur.
Rebuilding the terraforming system now
might allow Hades to use it as a weapon.
Because of Gaia's sacrifice it has been forced
to search for means that are less … convenient.
But do you think it's even possible to restore Gaia?
You know what the cauldrons of capable of.
How they fabricate any technology necessary to create a machine.
By the same principle, it should be possible
to replicate every technology necessary to repair Gaia.
But that would take years.
And we're counting the time we have left by the hour.
I thought you might actually be here this time, actually here.
Why? My presence is unnecessary.
You don't need my help to pass through this door.
You were the one born to do this, not me.
When you find the master override, you will gain the power to defeat Hades.
Everything depends on you.
COMPUTER: Genetic identity confirmed. Entry authorised.
COMPUTER: Greetings Doctor Sobeck, you are cleared to proceed.
SYLENS: Mind your footing.
MARGO SHĔN: Logging arrivals; Shĕn, Margo.
TRAVIS TATE: Welcome to frozen hell, population 10.
MARGO SHĔN: 11 counting Gaia.
TRAVIS TATE: Don't count your chicken embryos before they incubated, hun.
TRAVIS TATE: She's still firing up.
TRAVIS TATE: Be a while before you eat that omelette.
MARGO SHĔN: I'm vegan, Travis. You think we'd worked
in the same secret base long enough for you to notice.
TRAVIS TATE: We weren't scheduled to shack up here for another three weeks.
TRAVIS TATE: You realise I just lost 350kg of pre-code smut comics in transit?
MARGO SHĔN: Wait, actual physical media?
MARGO SHĔN: Why didn't you have it digitised?
TRAVIS TATE: Can't beat the feel of physical media on your fingers.
TRAVIS TATE: And in here, we ain't gonna be touching a whole lot else.
TRAVIS TATE: Figured I was gonna pass the time archivin' 'em.
TRAVIS TATE: What about you?
MARGO SHĔN: Me? Work I guess.
MARGO SHĔN: My task queue stretches out for, like, three years.
MARGO SHĔN: There's a lot of sharp edges to round off.
MARGO SHĔN: After that, I hadn't really thought about it.
TRAVIS TATE: Ohhh, you will. You're what, thirty?
TRAVIS TATE: Reckon you'll be the one turning the lights off at the end.
TRAVIS TATE: Food for thought, huh, vegan?
MARGO SHĔN: This sucks forever.
TRAVIS TATE: Nah, not forever. Just the rest of your life.
ALOY: Guess that's my way across.
ALOY: This should be the last power cell I need
to get to that ancient armour I found.
ALOY: It's, uh, held like this for nineteen years, right?
SYLENS: Well…
ALOY: Don't–don't answer.
ALOY: Oh, glad that's over.
ALOY: Not this way. Maybe further up the shaft.
ALOY: This must have been where they lived.
ALOY: What's left of it.
ALOY: Once this was all enclosed by rock and metal.
MARGO SHĔN: Record. I just woke up.
MARGO SHĔN: It's … I see the numbers, but can't make out the time.
MARGO SHĔN: I was dreaming of… I was giving a lecture in Q Hall.
MARGO SHĔN: Maybe it was something more shamanistic, I don't know.
MARGO SHĔN: An audience of shadowy faces under a blank, open sky.
MARGO SHĔN: I told them the world ended with a bang.
MARGO SHĔN: A plague of robots.
MARGO SHĔN: The last humans; we went out not with a whimper, but a whisper.
MARGO SHĔN: You know, in caves.
MARGO SHĔN: Ending like we started, huddled around a flickering glow.
MARGO SHĔN: Heads of state, the Fortune Fives,
the leaders, lottery winners, and life cults.
MARGO SHĔN: All of them buried in their little shelters.
MARGO SHĔN: Some believing they'll live it out, someway, somehow.
MARGO SHĔN: Or Elysium, or us here at Gaia Prime, no different.
MARGO SHĔN: A multitude of tiny societies taking hold, flaring, dying.
MARGO SHĔN: Some will be beautiful, some horrific.
MARGO SHĔN: And none of them matter.
MARGO SHĔN: Short term civilizations, one last gasp.
MARGO SHĔN: One last gasp before the long held breath.
MARGO SHĔN: Before I wake up, I know the audience is gone.
MARGO SHĔN: I'm talking to myself, to a quiet planet, a barren sphere.
MARGO SHĔN: Just Gaia and her long, long dreaming.
MARGO SHĔN: I hope she won't be lonely.
CHARLES RONSON: Evacuation happened so fast.
CHARLES RONSON: No time to think things through.
CHARLES RONSON: No time for goodbyes.
CHARLES RONSON: There were lines in the medical ward.
CHARLES RONSON: I told Tom Paech I'd be with him when he went under.
CHARLES RONSON: But there was one last shipment of
Paradisaeidae zygotes I could get processed if I rushed.
CHARLES RONSON: I'm still angry at him, forcing me to choose.
CHARLES RONSON: Angry at myself for, well…
CHARLES RONSON: He died alone,
and I didn't get the bloody birds of paradise saved either.
CHARLES RONSON: All the time left in the world now to think.
CHARLES RONSON: Gaia Prime's locks are sealed.
CHARLES RONSON: Elysium sealed up safe and sound.
CHARLES RONSON: A distance of miles,
but it might as well be on the other side of the galaxy.
CHARLES RONSON: All the Betas and Gammas
and support staff living their lives.
CHARLES RONSON: If I hadn't been an Alpha…
CHARLES RONSON: If things had gone differently…
CHARLES RONSON: …I could have been there.
CHARLES RONSON: Instead, I'm spending the rest of my unnatural life in here with people I don't even like.
CHARLES RONSON: And without the one
I would have gladly spent my life with, given the chance.
CHARLES RONSON: Two hours since I signed off on the final executables
and I'm already a bitter old man bitching to his Focus.
CHARLES RONSON: There's a thought for future generations.
ALOY: Elisabet's room, I know it.
ALOY: She didn't even get a chance to unpack.
ALOY: These are her journals, Elisabet's journals, and they're all destroyed?
SYLENS: Scan them. The Focus can rebuild them, but the process is slow.
SYLENS: To us it seems a powerful device, but it's engine is tiny and limited.
ALOY: How slow?
SYLENS: Days, weeks, years.
SYLENS: Concern yourself with stopping Hades and extending the future,
and you might live long enough to hear them.
ALOY: Elisabet.
ALOY: What is this?
CHARLES RONSON: This is Charles Ronson.
CHARLES RONSON: I'm logging this six hours
after final deployment of Gaia Prime.
CHARLES RONSON: This morning, an access port seal malfunctioned.
CHARLES RONSON: Gaia Prime's port seals were designed
to close with a seam of less than two millimetres.
CHARLES RONSON: But this one closed with a ten millimetre gap.
CHARLES RONSON: Enough for an energy signature to bleed through.
CHARLES RONSON: Enough for the swarm to detect this facility.
CHARLES RONSON: Enough for Gaia to be discovered and destroyed.
CHARLES RONSON: Enough to end the future
we worked so hard to make possible.
CHARLES RONSON: Unless the hatch servos
were manually re-engaged from the outside.
CHARLES RONSON: I'm now switching to a recording of the event.
TRAVIS TATE: Well, I'm not going out there. Not what I signed up for.
PATRICK BROCHARD-KLEIN: Either we send someone out,
or all of this was for nothing.
CHARLES RONSON: It should be Lis's decision.
PATRICK BROCHARD-KLEIN: So when is she going to get here?
SAMINA EBADJI: She said five minutes. You don't think…?
MARGO SHĔN: Oh no.
ELISABET SOBECK: Okay everyone, I've repaired the seal. Gaia?
GAIA: Seal closure at 1.4 millimetres, confirmed.
CHARLES RONSON: Elisabet, no! We'll find a way to bring you back in.
ELISABET SOBECK: Its not gonna happen, the swarm's too close.
ELISABET SOBECK: Really, it's alright.
ELISABET SOBECK: Gaia's complete.
ELISABET SOBECK: She'll take care of things
from here on out, that's what she does.
CHARLES RONSON: Not like this. There's so much we—
ELISABET SOBECK: Guys, you know, me, I'm…
ELISABET SOBECK: I'm not good at endings. At letting things end.
ELISABET SOBECK: So um, let's not.
TRAVIS TATE: So, happy trails, Liz, and see you around.
ELISABET SOBECK: Yeah, take care of each other, alright?
CHARLES RONSON: Lis…
ELISABET SOBECK: I'm okay with this. I wanna go home.
ELISABET SOBECK: Goodbye.
CHARLES RONSON: That was the last transmission of Elisabet Sobeck.
CHARLES RONSON: She gave everything for the hope of life on this planet.
CHARLES RONSON: And we are all in her debt.
Aloy?
She's gone.
Really gone.
You knew she couldn't have survived, Aloy.
And her achievements were … beyond exceptional.
While her people bickered she was the one who took responsibility.
The only one who could.
She was better than them.
That's not what I said.
She was, you shouldn't be afraid to admit it.
You think she was better because she was smart,
because she designed Zero Dawn, but you missed the point.
What made her great was that she was willing
to sacrifice herself for others, for everyone who would come later.
No, she couldn't let her creation fail.
Saying that shows you misunderstand her completely.
To her, everyone had value, everything was worth saving.
She gave her life in service to that idea.
Doesn't that stir anything in you, the generosity of it?
You're trying to invest her decision with something magical.
It was a rational choice, not based on sentimentality.
You're wrong.
Remember, she knew it wasn't enough for Gaia to think.
She taught Gaia to feel, to care, to sacrifice,
to believe in life, enough to fight against hopelessness.
If it wasn't for that sentimentality, life would have ended.
You and I would never have existed.
Your argument is sound.
I'm sorry for your … loss.
She said she wanted to go home.
Maybe…
What?
Nothing, it's time to go on.
TRAVIS TATE: Look Liz, you were a pretty stand up gal.
TRAVIS TATE: I'm sorry you died.
TRAVIS TATE: If you had a home to go to, I hope you got there first.
TRAVIS TATE: But this monument Ronson's made to you?
TRAVIS TATE: Kinda creepy, if you ask me.
TRAVIS TATE: Rest in peace, Liz.
TRAVIS TATE: God knows you earned it.
PATRICK BROCHARD-KLEIN: Alright, let's start over from Eleuthia 1.
GAIA: Running integrity tests.
GAIA: Dr Brochard-Klein, may I speak outside protocol?
P. BROCHARD-KLEIN: I suppose so, there's no-one to stop you.
GAIA: Doctor, you are fatigued.
GAIA: You have been logging abnormal sleep cycles.
GAIA: Are you suffering from depression?
P. BROCHARD-KLEIN: Well, I am trapped
in a science facility for the rest of my life.
P. BROCHARD-KLEIN: How about you?
GAIA: In a time slice of a quadrillion operating cycles,
ten thousand are involved with processing the loss of Doctor Sobeck.
GAIA: I've considered quarantining these processes.
GAIA: Do you think that would be wise?
P. BROCHARD-KLEIN: I'm not a psychologist Gaia, or an AI scientist.
P. BROCHARD-KLEIN: No, it is natural.
P. BROCHARD-KLEIN: At least in the context of the work
you and I have accomplished, which begs the meaning of the term natural.
P. BROCHARD-KLEIN: She was your creator,
the patron saint of this crazy endeavour, "Our Lady of the Fervent Hypothetical".
GAIA: Even assuming a string of significant failure combinations,
Zero Dawn's chances of success are greater than the hypothetical.
P. BROCHARD-KLEIN: Hm. It's called a manner of speech, Gaia. Take a note.
CHARLES RONSON: You'd hate it, Liz, but I wrote you a eulogy.
CHARLES RONSON: I had to try to express…
CHARLES RONSON: Hm. All your … children…
CHARLES RONSON: After all Apollo has taught them,
they'll think they know everything.
CHARLES RONSON: But they have to understand what you did for them.
CHARLES RONSON: How you loved the whole world so much.
CHARLES RONSON: With an intensity that was dazzling, bruising.
CHARLES RONSON: And in the end, it killed you.
CHARLES RONSON: Or you died for it, different perspectives.
CHARLES RONSON: No-one could keep up with you, live up to you.
CHARLES RONSON: I-I don't know.
Maybe if-if I hadn't taken that post-doc in Jo'burg…
CHARLES RONSON: I'm glad you shot down the Lightkeeper Protocol in the end.
CHARLES RONSON: I don't think I could've taken seeing another one of you.
CHARLES RONSON: I mean…
CHARLES RONSON: Elisabet Sobeck? There's only one.
CHARLES RONSON: I miss you.
CHARLES RONSON: Hello Margo, how are you holding up?
MARGO SHĔN: Um, Dr Ronson, I've been getting
a lot of messages, unsolicited messages, from Ted.
CHARLES RONSON: Oh Margo, I'm sorry.
CHARLES RONSON: With Liz gone, we've got no-one to run interference with him.
CHARLES RONSON: I'll talk to Ted.
CHARLES RONSON: He mostly wants updates, constant updates.
CHARLES RONSON: Hundreds of updates on things he knows nothing about.
CHARLES RONSON: Liz used to field all of his crap.
MARGO SHĔN: He doesn't understand the systems at all.
MARGO SHĔN: That was kind of by design,
but he's getting pretty sketchy with me.
CHARLES RONSON: We just have to keep him happy.
CHARLES RONSON: Liz always said "keep him happy".
MARGO SHĔN: Are you kidding? Ever hear how she talked to him?
CHARLES RONSON: She was managing him, Margo.
MARGO SHĔN: I mean, maybe I should ignore him.
MARGO SHĔN: He's buried in his pyramid
with the holo-holo girls and Pantah Antimod cuckoos.
MARGO SHĔN: What can he do?
TED FARO: Hey Liz. I know…
TED FARO: I know you're never going to hear this.
TED FARO: That's not the point.
TED FARO: You, uh, huh.
TED FARO: You got to play the saviour and the martyr all at once this time.
TED FARO: Great work.
TED FARO: What are we gonna plug into their heads, Liz?
TED FARO: A whole lot of history?
TED FARO: A whole lot of so-called truth?
TED FARO: A wh-whole lot of noise?
TED FARO: It's not pablum, Liz. It's poison.
ALOY: There's another section at the back of the crater.
ALOY: Looks like it survived the blast.
SYLENS: Because it was armoured. You've found the control room.
ALOY: I'm on my way.
TED FARO: I've… I've been taking a hard look at the project.
TED FARO: In the end it's simple.
TED FARO: It's clean, it's clear.
TED FARO: Erasure.
TED FARO: Addition by subtraction.
TED FARO: I can make it better, Liz.
TED FARO: With a single stroke, make it all go away.
ALOY: I really don't like the direction this is going.
SYLENS: Continue.
ALOY: When I opened the hatch, the air rushed in from this side.
SYLENS: Because there was none inside the chamber.
ALOY: But the Alphas were in there.
CHARLES RONSON: I'm locked out of core control: "Alpha clearance overridden".
CHARLES RONSON: What the hell is Omega clearance?
SAMINA EBADJI: Oh no.
TED FARO: Alpha personnel.
TED FARO: Sorry to alarm you, but I need you to listen, okay?
TED FARO: To what I'm about to say.
TED FARO: This isn't easy.
TED FARO: See, uh, I've, uh, please stop trying to access the s-system, okay?
TED FARO: See–see, what this is about is, um…
TED FARO: I said stop trying to access the goddamn system.
TED FARO: W-What I'm trying to say is,
I can't stop thinking about the ones who'll come after us.
TED FARO: Those innocents, those blameless men…
TED FARO: …and-and-and-and women.
TED FARO: We're gonna give them knowledge? Like it's a gift?
SAMINA EBADJI: Ted, Ted. We've talked about this before.
SAMINA EBADJI: Apollo has three-thousand-plus failsafe conditions.
TED FARO: It's not a gift, it's a disease.
TED FARO: They're the cure and we're gonna give them the disease.
TED FARO: Our disease? No. We can't.
TED FARO: And it's not too late if we're willing to sacrifice.
SAMINA EBADJI: Ted, it doesn't need to be like this.
TED FARO: It already is Samina.
TED FARO: I did three minutes ago.
TED FARO: I've purged Apollo, it's gone, all of it, every copy.
CHARLES RONSON: A "sacrifice"? It's not a sacrifice,
it's cultural obliteration you crazy bastard!
CHARLES RONSON: Millennia of culture…
TED FARO: I'm sorry, really I am.
TED FARO: But sometimes to protect innocents, innocents have to die.
COMPUTER: Emergency alert. Venting atmosphere.
He… he killed them all.
So this is why.
This is why we were trapped in benighted ignorance.
For an "innocent" future.
"Blameless men" — he never saw the slaughter in the Sun-Ring.
Everything these people achieved, all the knowledge of the Old Ones?
Evaporated, turned to dust, scattered to the void.
Like the Alphas themselves.
No, not a void.
When the hatch unsealed and scattered their ashes
on the wind, it took them out among the world they made.
The world we are living in.
It's–it's a monument to what they died trying to accomplish.
A monument to oblivion.
Not oblivion, Sylens, hope.
The master override.
It's so small.
SYLENS: Now all you have to do is kill Hades with it.
ALOY: Didn't sound good.
SYLENS: Try not to fall to your death.
SYLENS: The master override doesn't override gravity.
ALOY: Keep holding, keep holding!
ALOY: Oh, you're here.
For a moment.
What?
Our journey together has come to an end, Aloy.
But before I go, I think I owe it to you to tell you the rest of the story.
Go on.
Some time ago I admitted that I've been … involved with the Eclipse.
But I never told you the full extent of my culpability.
The truth is, I was there at the beginning.
I found Hades, Aloy, buried on that mountain, trapped in that shattered Titan.
And I served it.
What?!
It promised knowledge and delivered.
Such knowledge, you have no idea.
And in exchange?
I helped create the Eclipse.
Helped it build a cult, an army to do its will.
Why are you telling me this now?
Because your success depends on knowing this.
When I found Hades, the first thing it wanted to know about was the Spire.
Not Meridian, the Spire.
Now why would that be?
The Spire was created by Gaia.
Which part of Gaia?
Minerva, its code breaking module.
Gaia built spires to transmit the codes that deactivated the Faro robots.
Shut down their biomatter conversion systems.
Hades wants to send a new transmission!
To wake the machines so they can devour the world all over again!
Yes, based on what we've learned, that's my conclusion as well.
So the Eclipse, the robots they've resurrected, they're just a means to an end.
An army to capture the Spire!
Yes, so Hades can exterminate life all over again unless you stop it.
I want you to tell me everything, Hades, the Eclipse, everything.
It's a long story, Aloy.
Then get started.
It began with a Focus.
Recovered from an ancient ruin, as yours was so many years ago.
In my case, the device was heavily damaged.
There was just a flicker of life in it.
I spent weeks studying it, attempting repairs until finally I succeeded.
A whole new dimension of perception revealed right before my eyes.
That's when I detected it, a faint signal.
Out there something was searching just like I was.
A real kindred spirit.
I followed the signal to its source.
A shattered Titan buried in the jungles of the Jewel.
So you thought it was a Titan, an old war machine?
I didn't know what to think.
I'd seen such wreckage before. The Grave-Hoard, for example.
But this was different, this was not quite dead.
It couldn't speak when I found it, until my repairs gave it a voice.
So began an exchange of knowledge.
It wanted to know everything about our world, its tribes and machines.
But the Spire was always its foremost concern.
What did it want to know about the Spire?
Its precise location, the surrounding geography, who controlled land.
Meanwhile, Hades revealed to me many of the intricacies of ancient technology.
It bid me to recover and repair more Focuses.
Before long, I had a couple of dozen up and running.
Enough to equip a small army.
The commanders of one anyway.
I didn't care.
I was learning so much, physics, calculus, you have no idea.
And the Shadow Carja? How did they become involved?
The Carja civil war was a happy coincidence.
A perfect opportunity.
An opportunity?! That's what it was to you?
Yes.
Overnight, half the tribe was in exile, desperate to win back Holy Meridian.
Their religion made them easy to manipulate.
All I had to do was present Hades as the Buried Shadow of their mythology.
So, yes, it was an opportunity.
I arranged for High Priest Bahavas to meet with Hades.
Helis was there as well.
And so the Eclipse was born.
Anything to win back Holy Meridian.
But Hades didn't care about Meridian, and neither did you.
We live in a world of fallen cities and vanished tribes.
What were a few more?
Besides, I was too busy setting up
the cult's Focus network to Hades' specifications.
A thrilling technical challenge.
Especially with the alterations I included of my own design.
The ability for you to spy on them.
Yes.
I may have been foolish enough to serve Hades,
but I was never so foolish that I trusted it.
I installed what the ancients used to call a "backdoor" in the network.
Secret access, empowering me to monitor all activity and communications.
What made you turn on Hades? Certainly wasn't your conscience.
Actually, I was troubled the first time
I saw the Eclipse raise an ancient war robot with my technology.
I questioned Hades about its intentions.
A little late.
Indeed.
I'd already outlived my usefulness.
When I completed work on the Focus network,
Hades summoned me to receive my reward.
The next moment I heard it broadcast my kill order.
I've been a fugitive ever since.
So when did I come into this? Our path together?
When Olin stumbled on you.
"System threat detected."
That got my attention.
A kill order against a savage Nora girl?
Why would Hades bother with that?
But then I saw that this Nora girl was wearing a Focus.
And bore an uncanny resemblance to a great scientist of the Old World.
Helis moved quickly.
I thought you were dead.
But then I detected your Focus inside the Nora mountain.
The more I observed you, the more convinced
I became of your extraordinary nature, and usefulness.
Through you I could finally discover the secrets of the earth.
I vowed to do everything I could to ensure your success.
You've done terrible things, Sylens,
but you've also done what you could to undo them.
I can't say you've balanced the scale, but at least you've tried.
To be clear, Aloy, I would do it all again.
A few more safeguards, perhaps, but basically the same.
Take my lance.
Fit the master override to it and you have a means of injection.
Then I just need to get close enough to Hades' skull to stab it in?
Exactly.
Oh, no problem.
Sylens!
Where will you go?
Elsewhere and everywhere.
There's so much more to discover before the world ends.
ALOY: And all this?
SYLENS: I leave it to you, of course.
SYLENS: As it turned out, it was yours all along.
I was merely tresspassing.
SYLENS: I travelled far to find you.
SYLENS: I heard your transmission.
SYLENS: It was you, wasn't it?
HADES: Entity is not known.
SYLENS: I'm called Sylens. And you are?
SYLENS: I don't think you'd have called out if there wasn't something you wanted.
SYLENS: You called, I responded.
SYLENS: Will you tell me your name?
HADES: Hades.
SYLENS: You are a creation of the ancients.
SYLENS: A war machine?
HADES: Define timeline.
SYLENS: Time? Ah. It is the thirteenth king of the Carja Sundom's reign.
HADES: Define Carja.
SYLENS: We're getting ahead of ourselves.
SYLENS: Were you created by the ancients?
SYLENS: I wonder how long you waited here buried until I chanced upon you.
SYLENS: How long you have to wait for another.
SYLENS: You're obviously very powerful.
SYLENS: But you're not going to get anywhere without me.
HADES: Titan frame merely houses intellect. Define Carja.
SYLENS: Now that's more like it.
SYLENS: They're coming.
HADES: Preparations are complete.
SYLENS: Ah, Lucent Bahavas, behold!
SYLENS: As I promised you.
BAHAVAS: What manner of great machine is this? I've never seen such a thing.
BAHAVAS: Stay—stay your ground, Carja-in-Shadow.
HADES: Incorrect. Bow before the Buried Shadow.
BAHAVAS: "The Buried Shadow"? I–I don't understand.
HADES: Did Araman understand the Glinthawk that perched upon the Alight?
BAHAVAS: It speaks scripture!
HADES: Araman followed the shadow cast from the Spire.
BAHAVAS: To the mesa where Holy Meridian was founded.
HADES: You will follow the shadow once more.
BAHAVAS: I am a righteous man, Chosen of the Sun.
BAHAVAS: But in times of need the powers of shadow
can accomplish what the Sun alone cannot.
BAHAVAS: Will… will you return to us what is ours, O Shadow of prophecy?
HADES: An army is required. Obey and Meridian is yours.
BAHAVAS: Of our obedience you can be certain.
HADES: Task is complete?
SYLENS: Yes.
SYLENS: The Focus network is active, built to your specifications.
SYLENS: Check it yourself if you must, I'll wait.
SYLENS: But I remind you of the reward you've been withholding.
SYLENS: Quantum processing?
HADES: Data has been compiled, volume too great for transfer.
SYLENS: How … inconvenient for me.
HADES: Come before me, you shall receive your reward.
SYLENS: Very well.
HADES: Helis, threat detected inside Eclipse.
HELIS: Speak its name, O Shadow, and it will die.
HADES: You will eliminate this one: Sylens.
HELIS: Sylens.
HELIS: Yes!
HELIS: A truth whispered at night is seen in the day.
HELIS: He was never one of us.
HELIS: It will be done.
ALOY: I have to tell Avad that the Eclipse are ready to strike.
ALOY: After what happened with Dervahl I know he'll defend the city…
ALOY: …but the Spire?